Finding Aid for the Papers of Virginia Woolf, 1902-1956
Mortimer Rare Book Room, William Allan Neilson Library, Smith College
- Series III. Manuscripts by Virginia Woolf
  - Italian: autograph manuscript notebook, 1916 Jun 7., 70 leaves (87 pages). (Box 3, Folder 175)
    Begins with lesson XXXI. Includes notes, translations, and exercises in Virginia Woolf's hand from an Italian grammar. Purchased.
  - Letters: Virginia Woolf &Lytton Strachey
    See: box 1, folders 1-144
  - Orlando., Orange quarter leather case for page proofs. (Box 4, Folder 176)
  - Orlando: page proofs, corrected, 1928., 155 leaves (310 pages). (Box 4, Folder 177)
    Inscribed by author: Corrected page proofs for Mr Gaige. Proofs stamped: FIRST PROOF, R. &R. CLARK, LTD., EDINBURGH, 9-14 JUN. 1928; THIRD PROOF, R. &R. CLARK, LTD., EDINBURGH, 18 JUL. 1928. Printer's annotation on page 257 of the third proof: July 22, 1928. Includes a later proof of pages 257-272. Corrected by Virginia Woolf for the American edition (published 2 Oct 1928 by Crosby Gaige in a limited edition; 18 Oct 1928 by Harcourt, Brace, and Company in a trade edition). Printers annotations throughout.
  - "The Patron and the Crocus": holograph, 1924 Feb 26-Mar 15, 14 leaves (14 pages). (Box 4, Folder 178)
    See also: The Common Reader, Box 3, folder 174.
  - Reading notes on Sons and Lovers by D. H. Lawrence: holograph, [1931], 3 leaves (3 pages). (Box 4, Folder 179)
  - Reading notes on novels by Anthony Trollope, Thomas Peacock, Honore de Balzac, Leo Tolstoy, and Samuel Richardson: holograph, 1926, 22 leaves (22 pages). (Box 4, Folder 180)
    With Hogarth Press envelope. Includes Anna Karenina by Tolstoy, Clarissa Harlowe by Richardson, Crotchet Castle by Peacock, Eugenie Gradet by Balzac, and The Warden by Trollope.
  - "Reviewing," typescript, corrected, [1939], 19 leaves (19 pages). (Box 4, Folder 181)
    Gift of Ann Safford Mandel, with "The Searchlight."
  - Roger Fry: holograph notes, [1938], 33 leaves (33 pages). With Hogarth Press envelope. (Box 4, Folder 182)
  - The Roger Fry Memorial Exhibition: [1935], typescript (carbon), corrected, 6 leaves (6 pages). (Box 4, Folder 183)
    Address given by Virginia Woolf.
  - "The Searchlight": [1939], typescript, corrected, 8 leaves (8 pages). (Box 4, Folder 184)
    Gift of Ann Safford Mandel.
  - "The Searchlight," [1941], holograph, 6 leaves (6 pages). (Box 4, Folder 185)
  - To the Lighthouse., Orange quarter leather case for page proofs. (Box 5, Folder 186)
  - To the Lighthouse: 1927., page proofs, corrected, 186 leaves (370 pages). (Box 5, Folder 187-89)
    Stamped: FIRST PROOF, R. &R. CLARK, LTD., EDINBURGH, 1927 JAN 13-FEB 12. Includes two sets of corrected proofs for pages 273-322. Corrected by Virginia Woolf for the American edition (published 5 May 1927 by Harcourt, Brace, and Company). Printer's annotations throughout.
- Series IV. Hogarth Press Ephemera
  - 1917. Prospectus for Two Stories (No. 1)
    See: box 1, folder 66.
  - 1921. Advertisement for The Note-Books of Anton Tchekhov together with Reminiscences of Tchehkov by Maxim Gorky. (No. 14) (Box 5, Folder 190)
  - 1921. Advertisement for The Note-Books of Anton Tchekhov (No. 14) and previous publications (Box 5, Folder 191)
  - 1921. Advertisement for Stories of the East by Leonard Woolf (No. 16) (Box 5, Folder 192)
  - 1921. Advertisement for Monday or Tuesday by Virginia Woolf (No. 17) (Box 5, Folder 193)
  - 1924 Nov 11 Hogarth Press invoice.
    See: box 2, folder 118
  - 1927. [Lopokova, Lydia] Interpretations. (No. 128.1) (Box 5, Folder 194)
    Gift of Elizabeth Power Richardson.
  - 1929. Hogarth Press. Virginia Woolf New Uniform Edition., 3 copies. (Box 5, Folder 195)
    Catalogue of The Voyage Out, Jacob's Room, Mrs. Dalloway, and The Common Reader. Gift of Elizabeth Power Richardson.
  - 1930. Hogarth Press. Two New Novels. (Box 5, Folder 196)
    Catalogue of Dawn on Mont Blanc by Wilfred Benson (No. 216) and Occupied Territory by Alice Ritchie (No. 233). Gift of Elizabeth Power Richardson.
  - 1932. Hogarth Press. Autumn List. (Box 5, Folder 197)
  - 1932. Hogarth Press. Complete Catalogue of Works in Print. (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - 1932. Hogarth Press. The Works of Virginia Woolf., 3 copies. (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - 1939. Advertisement for Hogarth Sixpenny Pamphlets (Nos. 445, 459, 443, 442). (Box 5, Folder 200)
- Series V. Manuscripts by Others, 1904-1926
  - Aldington, Richard to Virginia Woolf, 1926 Jan 23, TLS
    See: box 2, folder 123.
  - Bennett, Arnold, "Books & Persons": holograph, [1926 Dec?], 3 leaves (3 pages). (Box 5, Folder 201)
    From Hugh Walpole's library. Essay about three books by Virginia Woolf: The Common Reader, Mrs. Dalloway, and Jacob's Room.
  - Brace, Donald C. to Crosby Gaige, 1925 Jul 14, ALS
    See: box 3, folder 171
  - Ritchie, Anne Thackeray to Mr. Darwin, [1904], ALS, 4 leaves (4 pages). (Box 5, Folder 202)
    Bound with TLS, Laurence Gomme to Frances Hooper, 1952 Sep 2, and chronology of Anne Thackeray Ritchie. Binding stamped: Anne Ritchie's original letter about Leslie Stephen.
  - Strachey, James. Holograph notes and preface to Letters: Virginia Woolf &Lytton Strachey.
    See: box 1, folders 1-2.
  - Strachey, Lytton, to James Strachey, 1909 Mar 9, Typescript extract.
    See: box 1, folder 32.
  - Woolf, Leonard to Lytton Strachey, 1912 Jun 6, ALS.
    See: box 1, folder 45.
  - Woolf, Leonard to Lytton Strachey, 1918 May 24, TLS.
    See: box 1, folder 77
  - Woolf, Leonard to Lytton Strachey, [1918 Jun 11], Telegram.
    See: box 1, folder 78.
- Series VI. Photographs, 1902-1927
  - George Beresford, Virginia Stephen, 1902 (modern print). (Box 6, Folder 203)
    Bloomsbury Iconography A33.
    Gift of Blanche Cooney.
  - Virginia Woolf at Garsington, 1923?, Framed. (Box 6, Folder 204)
    Bloomsbury Iconography B19.
    Purchased 1988.
  - Virginia Woolf, circa 1927. (Box 6, Folder 205)
    Bloomsbury Iconography B52.
    Gift of Esther Dunn, 1977.